{"posts":[{"intent":"assignments","courseCode":"COMP1531","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"assignments","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"group project - milestones 1 and 2","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"group project specification","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"hi i'm wondering if implementing the following would be a good design currently our providers and patients and healthcentres are all stored in one object and that object returns those items given differing parameters such as id or email or a search term . would it be better to have a searching object and for us to inject into that object an object that holds either providers patients or healthcentres where each of these objects have the same methods . part of the reason why i'm asking is that the searching object and the object containing the patients providers healthcentres should have an aggregation relationship but when you pass an object like def __init__ self object does this not make the relationship between these objects a composition","answers":[{"text":"hi ricky both your current approach and the suggested approach seems acceptable as i can see that they both hold their own benefits. i will not be giving a definite answer but i would like to make some suggestions 1st approach lists of providers patients and health centres in an object that allows access to the items of desired criteria - although the container object say a provides the methods for searching/querying please think about whether a really should contain the logic for searching/querying think about single responsibility principle cohesion coupling etc. - i recommend you to have a look into the data access object pattern and how it handles the case like yours. fully applying the pattern is likely to be an overkill but the motivation behind it and how it improves the design is something to take a note of. 2nd approach searching object - in this case the classes patient provider and centre should all inherit from the same parent class that abstracts over the common searching methods across the three concrete classes. and in light of ocp amp dip your searching object should only depend on such methods i.e. depend only on the higher level module . - however please note that patients providers and centres have different criteria with which they will be queried for e.g. centres by suburb providers by service type . this makes it difficult to abstract out their commonalities - in this case you should ask yourself whether this really is a flexible design i am not saying it s definitely bad just saying that you should take extra care - if this cannot be implemented easily try not to overcomplicate the code or introduce unnecessary complexity by blindly applying the design principles - sometimes simple designs are better. as for the second question passing in an object a as a parameter to the constructor of object b does not necessarily imply a composition relationship - the thing with class-to-class relationship is that it depends on the situation. a composition relationship holds whenever the lifetime of the contained object depends on the lifetime of the container object and passing in the contained object as a parameter to the constructor of the container object is just one way to allow such relationship to hold but it does not necessarily enforce it - why . cheers random babble on design please be aware that it is completely fine to use simpler design when there is no issue with the design i.e. sometimes applying the design principles too early introduces unnecessary complexity and involves you guessing the direction of change in the specs which may not be clear at the time of implementation or a change may not even occur in which case you would have had done unnecessary work - yagni . on the other hand simpler designs are often more comprehensible and can be transformed more flexibly to the changes in the requirements through refactoring. this is because the design principles are principles not laws that you must always follow. that being said some designs bring benefits immediately to the system and a simple design may be completely awful when the system itself becomes large or complex e.g. a series of if statements checking for the type of an object this suggests that you should make use polymorphism to improve the design so you must be judicious with applying this idea.","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"intent":"assignments","courseCode":"COMP1531","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"assignments","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"group project - milestones 1 and 2","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"group project specification","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"hi i'm having trouble with github. i've committed my contributions and i can see them but according to my teammates my contributions are not recorded and i'm not considered a contributor. can someone help please","answers":[{"text":"i've emailed your student email in regards to this.","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"intent":"assignments","courseCode":"COMP1531","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"assignments","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"group project - milestones 1 and 2","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"group project specification","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"hi is it possible to login two different types of users in one application right now our group's code is structured into patients being a composition with patientmanager and providers being a composition with providermanager etc so i made a page for logging in patients and another for logging in providers. login only works for either the patient/the provider depending on which form you have filled in first. is there a workaround to this or do i have to change how the classes are structured i.e. have patients and providers inherit from user and then define user access roles thanks. edit nevermind i changed it to inheritance and it works. however i'm still unsure on how to define user access roles properly.","answers":[{"text":"hi angela there is an example code provided for lab08 authenticationmanager.py and its usage in routes.py that handles different user permissions - please checkout it out and try to analyse how it works. please feel free to ask if you would like some help with that","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"intent":"assignments","courseCode":"COMP1531","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"assignments","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"group project - milestones 1 and 2","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"group project specification","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"to any who can help i'm getting an error from my redirect function call typeerror centre missing 1 required positional argument 'centre' this suggests to me that theres something wrong with what im passing into the redirect but after playing around for a while i'm still not sure what it is. the route and function are as such app.route '/centre/ lt name gt ' def centre centre name return render_template 'centre.html' result centre the html call is like this lt div gt for c in result lt a href url_for 'centre' centre c name c.name gt c lt /a gt endfor lt /div gt any advice is appreciated.","answers":[{"text":"hi joshua app.route '/centre/ lt name gt ' only parameterises the name argument since it is the only one in between the angular brackets - so in fact your centre method currently can only take in one parameter name and not centre . please have another go at fixing your issue with that in mind. hint another pair of lt gt may help please tell me if you cannot still resolve the issue.","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"intent":"assignments","courseCode":"COMP1531","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"assignments","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"group project - milestones 1 and 2","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"group project specification","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"all i wondered is that whether it is okay for me to create a html for each provider and centre or just create one template then fill everything in","answers":[{"text":"it's fine if you want to create html for each provider. if you just use one template you will not lose mark as well.","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"i didn't quite get it for each provider and centre i created a html file but they are in same layout is that okay","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"it's okay. by the way if you think they are in same layout why seperate","theta":1,"count":0}]]]},{"intent":"assignments","courseCode":"COMP1531","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"assignments","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"group project - milestones 1 and 2","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"group project specification","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"with regards to getter and setter methods would it be better for the object itself to have a getter method e.g. list healthprovider.get or if we were to have a list of objects stored in a 'manager' for that manager to get the object information i.e. str healthprovider.name..","answers":[{"text":"a class that models a health-care provider e.g. class healthprovider would have getter and setter if needed methods that would return and set details about the particular provider. if you wanted to cache a list of health-care providers this would typically be stored in another class as list of providers which you would then be able to search for a particular provider by different criteria e.g. name","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"intent":"assignments","courseCode":"COMP1531","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"assignments","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"group project - milestones 1 and 2","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"group project specification","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"i am getting this error in my routes.py. i am unsure how to fix it werkzeug.exceptions.httpexception.wrap. lt locals gt .newcls 400 bad request keyerror 'password'","answers":[{"text":"hi aniket it is likely because you are trying to access a value of a dictionary e.g. request.form is a dictionary too with a key 'password' that does not exist this is similar to an invalid array index error for arrays. whenever you are accessing a dictionary value please make sure that the dictionary already has a corresponding key-value pair stored inside it.","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"intent":"assignments","courseCode":"COMP1531","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"assignments","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"group project - milestones 1 and 2","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"group project specification","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"for week 9 does our uml class diagram need to include even ones that are not needed to be implemented yet i.e. rating/notes/prescriptions","answers":[{"text":"hi paulo you only need to include the ones that belong to this milestone","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"intent":"assignments","courseCode":"COMP1531","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"assignments","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"group project - milestones 1 and 2","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"group project specification","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"how can we implement near-match of string in python3","answers":[{"text":"hi haoran the definition of a near-match should have been provided in your acceptance criteria so it depends on how you have defined it. but in the case that you have not or if you would like hints as to implement such a functionality please have a look at the behaviour of the search engine example solution http //cgi.cse.unsw.edu.au/ cs1531/18s2/sample_project/run.cgi/. please think about what can be considered as a near match e.g. do capitalisations matter what if your search keyword is only a subset of the strings you are comparing against 'rand' in 'royal randwick' cheers","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"intent":"assignments","courseCode":"COMP1531","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"assignments","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"group project - milestones 1 and 2","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"group project specification","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"can we add more specific information to csv files due to the absence of name password working hour and so on","answers":[{"text":"yes you are free to modify csv files.","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"intent":"assignments","courseCode":"COMP1531","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"assignments","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"group project - milestones 1 and 2","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"group project specification","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"do we need to have our logbook on the release branch as well","answers":[{"text":"log book does not need to be uploaded to release branch. however you log book does need a velocity chart to show user story progress.","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"intent":"assignments","courseCode":"COMP1531","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"assignments","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"group project - milestones 1 and 2","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"group project specification","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"hi may i knw what does the four digit number in the second column eg.1111 in the health_centres.csv represent","answers":[{"text":"also is the fourth column phone number or","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"hi yin tan we will be soon releasing an updated version of the csv files that contain the column headings","theta":1,"count":0}]]},{"intent":"assignments","courseCode":"COMP1531","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"assignments","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"group project - milestones 1 and 2","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"group project specification","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"is it ok to ignore the class-managers when implementing them to python and just put all the methods which belong to managers under system and of course system should hold all the information it needs.","answers":[{"text":"that would still function normally yes. manager classes are mostly useful where you believe system is containing too much logic and you would like to split this logic up into cohesive classes.","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"intent":"assignments","courseCode":"COMP1531","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"assignments","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"group project - milestones 1 and 2","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"group project specification","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"is it okay to ignore trivial methods such as getters and setters in the class diagram also should the methods in class diagram have a return type along with their parameters","answers":[{"text":"classes should have getters and setters only if needed. for example if you do not want the instance variables to be updated by clients then this class should not define setters and the instance variables are set through the constructor. hence it is important to show these methods on the class diagram. and yes methods in class diagram must define the return type along with their parameters","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"intent":"assignments","courseCode":"COMP1531","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"assignments","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"group project - milestones 1 and 2","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"group project specification","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"for the class diagram with a method like makebooking would you have to specify all the parameters date time etc. with the method looking like makebooking str str .. or could you have a default constructor makebooking and have setters for the other variables i.e booking.settime 15 00 and would then you need to specify all of the setter methods","answers":[{"text":"makebooking str str.. makes sense to me.","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"intent":"assignments","courseCode":"COMP1531","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"assignments","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"group project - milestones 1 and 2","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"group project specification","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"how should methods that use property and x.setter decorators be represented in a uml diagram since the methods have the same name thank you","answers":[{"text":"great question just on the class diagram you may write get_password and set_password to indicate that your class provides a getter and a setter for the password attribute but of course you can keep the property decorators in your python code . this is acceptable since uml class diagram should be agnostic of the implementation language. also quick tip if you think you have too many getters and setters on your diagram think about whether all of them actually need to be implemented.","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"thank you","theta":1,"count":0}]]},{"intent":"assignments","courseCode":"COMP1531","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"assignments","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"group project - milestones 1 and 2","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"group project specification","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"hi i was looking through the specs and realised there isn't a defined list of services. is that intentional","answers":[{"text":"yup your application should be able to deduce the list of all services from other csv files.","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"so the program should be able to read the csv files and collect its information from there","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"yes definitely","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"thank you","theta":1,"count":0}]]]]},{"intent":"assignments","courseCode":"COMP1531","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"assignments","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"group project - milestones 1 and 2","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"group project specification","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"furthermore different health providers may have different workings hours and if a provider is affiliated with multiple centres then the provider will have different working hours associated with each centre how exactly does this work are the working hours the same each day or can they be different for different days of the week will the working hours with one centre be continuous or can you have something that looks like this centre 1 9am-12pm centre 2 1pm-5pm centre 1 6pm-9pm also can we add this information to the csv files as it doesn't currently seem to be specified anywhere","answers":[{"text":"for simplicity you can assume working hours are continuous and centres are open 24 hours. so you will only need to record the working hours of the health-care provider. so a provider may work 9-12 in centre 1 and 1-6 in centre 2. you can also assume that the hours don't conflict so you don't need to build in any error-handling to check if working hours across 2 centres clash","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"where do we get the working hours information from a further csv file or do we create it","theta":1,"count":0}]]},{"intent":"assignments","courseCode":"COMP1531","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"assignments","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"group project - milestones 1 and 2","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"group project specification","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"hi it seems that i don't have access to commit changes to project repository under cs1531 organization. is there anyone who could help me to solve this cheers","answers":[{"text":"check that the team member who created the group project repo has given you access rights to commit.","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"hi we are having the same issue and everyone in our group can't push commits.","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"hi ellen just a quick question did you create your group on github manually and not through the github app by any chance we are trying to locate the source the error at the moment. in the meanwhile i can fix the problem for your team if you could please give me your team name and class on github thanks d","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"i don't remember how we set it up it's possible. thanks it's h13a team name is csez","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"okay no worries. the access issue has been fixed for your group now by the way","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"hi could you help me to solve the same issue our group name is tidehunter class is h13a. cheer","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"di is your problem fixed. are your team members able to access now","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"it works now. thank you so much.","theta":1,"count":0}]]],[{"text":"thank you it is working d","theta":1,"count":0}]]]]]]},{"intent":"assignments","courseCode":"COMP1531","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"assignments","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"group project - milestones 1 and 2","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"group project specification","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"a patient should be able to view their own appointments history a chronological list of their current appointments with the health providers on hams . each entry on the list should contain links to the profile pages of the corresponding health provider and the corresponding health centre. hi does this refer to two separate lists one for past appointments and one for current appointments thanks","answers":[{"text":"hi michael the appointments history just refers to the appointments you have made history here is a bit misleading i guess so actually appointments history chronological list of the patient's current appointments on hams. with regards to showing past appointments you have a freedom to either display them or not depending on what you believe is reasonable for the patients. hopefully this cleared things up but please ask if you would like further clarification.","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"intent":"assignments","courseCode":"COMP1531","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"assignments","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"group project - milestones 1 and 2","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"group project specification","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"hi ae we allowed to have user stories which are not within an epic story i'm not sure whether logging in requires an entire epic story as logging in doesn't fall within our group's epic stories such as booking and searching. thanks in advance.","answers":[{"text":"hi angela it is completely fine to have a login user story under its own epic since as you said it may not fit well under other epics and it also answers the question of where you should place additional user stories if your client ever requests extra features related to login e.g. registration forgot my password to be added onto your system.","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"intent":"assignments","courseCode":"COMP1531","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"assignments","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"group project - milestones 1 and 2","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"group project specification","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"when it says 'patient past history' in the specs as show in the picture attached does it refer to appointment history or medical history such as diabetic heart attack surgery thank you.","answers":[{"text":"hi the patient's past history refers to the chronological list of the patient's appointments with the provider with added details such as the notes taken at previous visits.","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"intent":"assignments","courseCode":"COMP1531","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"assignments","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"group project - milestones 1 and 2","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"group project specification","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"how far beyond the specification do we need to go for the first submission in terms of things like being able to cancel a booking should we add these for later iterations","answers":[{"text":"do not implement something which is not currently required.","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"intent":"assignments","courseCode":"COMP1531","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"assignments","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"group project - milestones 1 and 2","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"group project specification","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"can we number user stories in according to the epic stories there associated with or to show related user stories. for example have epic story 3 us3.1 3.2 3.3 etc... and even us 3.3.1/us3.3.2 to show further breaking down of the user stories or should we just keep at as 1 2 3 .....","answers":[{"text":"numbering user-stories is mainly to uniquely identify a particular user-story and use this identifier later to associate for example the set of test-cases associated with this story. your convention for numbering stories sounds quite logical and would actually help to trace a particular fine-grained user-story to the epic story it is associated with. good thinking","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"intent":"assignments","courseCode":"COMP1531","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"assignments","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"group project - milestones 1 and 2","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"group project specification","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"do we need to block usernames that input incorrect passwords an x amount of times within a certain time frame","answers":[{"text":"hi adam as said in the answer to the question below this is up to you and your team's discretion to implement this feature if you feel that it is reasonable. however i personally feel that it is less important than other features that you have been asked to implement in the specification and i would recommend considering it as an optional/extension task after you have delivered higher priority user stories. nevertheless it would be great if you do have this additional feature included in the final product","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"intent":"assignments","courseCode":"COMP1531","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"assignments","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"group project - milestones 1 and 2","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"group project specification","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"is there a limit on how far in advance a user can book an appointment and therefore how far in advance the doctors availability must be given for","answers":[{"text":"as this is a granular detail that has not been covered by the specification of the assignment your team should discuss together to come up with a reasonable assumption regarding this matter - any decision is acceptable as long as it is well supported by reasons and value to the customer is well considered in the decision making. also please make sure to include your final decision in the assumptions list as requested in the assignment specs.","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"intent":"assignments","courseCode":"COMP1531","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"assignments","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"group project - milestones 1 and 2","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"group project specification","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"does a user need to be able to log out in iteration 1","answers":[{"text":"once you have implemented a login feature for the system logout should be very easy to implement. also logging-in and logging-out seem like features that are much better implemented together for easier testing and usability reasons so i would highly recommend doing so for the iteration 1.","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"intent":"assignments","courseCode":"COMP1531","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"assignments","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"group project - milestones 1 and 2","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"group project specification","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"about viewing appointment's history does the user only see their current appointments or also all previous/past appointments as well","answers":[{"text":"our model solution offered a way for a user to see their current appointments. once the doctor had been seen this appointment would be removed from their current appointment dashboard. a user however was able to see their past history with the doctor e.g notes taken by the doctor medication prescribed by clicking on the history tab. you can implement this functionality in different ways however the key point is a user needs to be able view their current appointments and also have the capability to view the doctor's notes in their previous appointments","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"intent":"assignments","courseCode":"COMP1531","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"assignments","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"group project - milestones 1 and 2","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"group project specification","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"what is the give command for the assignment our group has finished the tasks required for us to complete for this week. we've uploaded everything to github but what is the give command","answers":[{"text":"the give submission has not been setup. it will be done shortly.","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"thanks. do we all need to give the assignment or just one of us","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"just one member from the team.","theta":1,"count":0}]]]},{"intent":"assignments","courseCode":"COMP1531","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"assignments","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"group project - milestones 1 and 2","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"group project specification","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"hi for the user stories do we have to submit them with some kind of template i remember something about this briefly mentioned in the lectures but i'm not too sure. thanks","answers":[{"text":"a template has been uploaded to the assignment folder under the group project iteration 1","theta":1,"count":0}]}]}